Gail E. Terman

gterman@gmail.com

60 Cedar St, Newton, MA 02459 (617) 549-1121

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

Languages: Fluent in Java, Python, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, ¡Query/JavaScript

Experience in C#, C, HTML/CSS, Bash Scripting, Scheme/Racket

Systems: Windows 98/ME/XP/7, Ubuntu Linux, Mac OSX

Software: IntelliJ IDE, Unity, Eclipse IDE, Maven, DrScheme/DrRacket, Git Special Projects: Created first web page at age 9, build own gaming machines

WORK EXPERIENCE

Skillz, Inc., Boston, MA

Server Engineer

February 2014 – January 2015

- Designed and implemented the back-end for the customer loyalty rewards program, "Ticketz"
- Expanded internal admin portal functionality by integrating with internal RESTful APIs
- Maintained the customer-facing developer portal, used by developers to integrate the Skillz SDK
- Moved the company corporate website to a Rails project, making the content configurable
- Implemented the back-end for the Skillz web-app, which serves as a distribution platform
- Optimized and implemented database queries to search for fraudulent users on the Skillz system

Nectar Games, Seattle, WA

Programmer

January 2012 – June 2012

- Designed the architecture for a strategic combat game, and implemented part of the game in Unity
- Created, migrated, and maintained a version management repository (Subversion, Git)

DoubleTap Games, Boston, MA

Game Programming Intern

January 2011 – June 2011

- Designed and implemented the user interface for a Facebook application
- Implemented the server side of a system that allows the 3DS to transfer data to a website

Attivio Inc., Newton, MA

Java Developer Intern

July 2010 - December 2010

- Integrated custom search into the Confluence wiki engine using plugins
- Developed software components using Eclipse, Mayen, and Java

Penny Arcade Expo, Boston, MA; Seattle, WA; Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

Enforcer / Exhibitor Assistant / Enforcer Welfare Department Manager

March 2010 – Present

- Managed a team of Enforcers dedicated to providing care and support to 480 people who worked in a high activity environment over the course of 3 days
- Acted as a liaison between a specific set of exhibitors, the facility, and Penny Arcade

EDUCATION

Northeastern University, Boston, MA

January 2010 – December 2013

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

January 2014

College of Computer and Information Science

Related Courses: Systems and Networks, Software Development, Programming Languages,

Artificial Intelligence, Computer Architecture, Computer Graphics, Theory of Computation, Algorithms & Data, Game Design Algorithms

Activities: CISters, NU Choral Society

Major GPA: 3.70/4.00

INTERESTS

Music: Singing (a cappella, musical theater, opera, choral), playing flute, learning piano
Games: Puzzle games, RTS, turn-based strategy, casual games, board and card games
Other: Doing puzzles, crocheting and knitting, watching the Boston Red Sox, Girl Scouting

References will be supplied upon request